BACKEND SOFTWARE DEVELOPER

Nahuel Brandán







ABOUT ME -

Computer Analyst / Backend Software Developer, specialized in Python, with 3+ years of experience. Recently worked in the aerospace industry. I apply my skills and knowledge in the development of efficient and high-quality solutions. A promoter of constant improvement in technical documentation and application of good development practices.

EXPERIENCE -

Company: Satellogic | Backend Developer

06/2022 - 09/2022

Company, vertically integrated, specialized in earth observation satellites.

- Experienced in developing satellite flight applications using Python.
- Refactored an application into two separate entities, reducing coupling and improving maintainability.
- Dedicated to improving code quality through regular code reviews and technical discussions.

Company: <u>Ascentio</u> | Project: <u>Sabia-Mar</u> | Backend Developer

08/2021 - 05/2022

Sabia-Mar is a satellite mission, with advanced technology for the study of the sea and the ocean.

- Made contributions to the satellite flight planning and communication modules, utilizing technologies as: Python, Docker, FastAPI, and APIs.
- Developed both software and unit and integration validation tests, utilizing technologies as: Robot Framework, Postman, and Pytest.

Company: IncluIT | Project: Junar | Backend Developer

03/2019 - 07/2021

- Proficient in the development of applications using Python, Django, and Django Rest Framework.
- Implemented the integration of Autho and Keyclok for added security in API management.
- Executed an upgrade of Django versions and dependencies, resulting in a reduction of technical debt.
- Experienced in managing and caching data in various databases such as Elasticsearch, Redis, Celery.
- Technical onboarded +10 new developers to the team, providing technical guidance and support.

EDUCATION

B.S in Computer Science - (Graduated) | Academy: FaMAF - UNC

10/2018

Career with strong emphasis on programming, analysis and design of systems, databases and computer networks, combining a solid theoretical understanding with practical skills.

COURSES -

Self-study online courses | Academy: **Platzi**

01/2021 - Present

More than 100 courses completed and in constant learning in the professional online academy called Platzi, on various topics such as: soft skills, English, software development.

SKILLS -

- Programming languages: Python, C.
- Databases: MySQL, MongoDB, Redis, Elasticsearch.
- Frameworks: Django, Django REST Framework, FastAPI, Robot Framework.
- Dev tools: Linux, REST API, Git, GitHub, Bash, Postman, Autho, Docker, Celery.

LANGUAGES

- English: **B1 intermediate**.
- Spanish: Native.